Enter a new dimension of Strange.
Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness is a fantasy,
action, adventure film directed by Sam Raimi.
Doctor Strange, with the help of mystical allies both old and new, traverses the mind-bending and
dangerous alternate realities of the Multiverse to confront a mysterious new adversary.
Doctor Stephen Strange, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
America Chavez, played by Xochitl Gomez.
Wanda Maximoff / The Scarlet Witch, played by Elizabeth Olsen.
Baron Mordo, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Wong, played by Benedict Wong.
Dr. Christine Palmer, played by Rachel McAdams.
Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness is a 2022 American superhero film
based on Marvel Comics featuring the character Doctor Strange.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the sequel
to Doctor Strange (2016) and the 28th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Sam Raimi, written by Michael Waldron, and stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Stephen Strange,
alongside Elizabeth Olsen, Chiwetel Ejiofor, Benedict Wong, Xochitl Gomez, Michael Stuhlbarg, and Rachel McAdams.
In the film, Strange must protect America Chavez (Gomez), a teenager capable
of traveling the multiverse, from the Scarlet Witch (Olsen).
Doctor Strange director and co-writer Scott Derrickson
had plans for a sequel by October 2016.
He signed to return as director in December 2018, when
Cumberbatch was confirmed to return.
The film's title was announced in July 2019 along with Olsen's involvement, while
Jade Halley Bartlett was hired to write the film that October.
Derrickson stepped down as director in January
2020, citing creative differences.
Waldron and Raimi joined the following month and started over, adding elements of the horror genre that Raimi had worked with
previously and making Wanda the villain of the film, continuing her story from the Disney+ miniseries WandaVision (2021).
Filming began in November 2020 in London but was put on hold
in January 2021 due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
Production resumed by March 2021 and concluded in mid-April in Somerset.
Shooting also occurred in Surrey and Los Angeles.
With a production budget of $350.6 million, Doctor Strange in the
Multiverse of Madness is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness premiered at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on May
2, 2022, and was released in the United States on May 6, as part of Phase Four of the MCU.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $955.8
million worldwide, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2022.
The film explores themes of magic, superhero, based on
comic, alternative reality, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is mind_bending.